Amelia Wang

ameliawang35@gmail.com • wangamelia.github.io

UX Researcher

Hello! I've led and designed academic research studies for 5+ years in Human-Computer Interaction and I'm looking to transition into industry to bridge theory and impact. I am a researcher that leads with curiosity and empathy to inspire solutions and opportunities that are user-centered and empowering. I've had the opportunity to hold leadership positions for clubs and research planning with focus on relationships. Selected project summaries available on my portfolio at wangamelia.github.io

WORK EXPERIENCE

Tech4 Good Lab, University Of California Santa Cruz • 09/2020 - 04/2024

Research Assistant

- Mentored 20+ undergraduates and managed multiple research projects in sociotechnical systems and products, teaching on UX methodology concepts and user education, making and ensuring alignment with user needs. Essentially acting as a product manager, generating roadmaps and facilitating research along the product life cycle.
- Directed a team to discover 28+ product opportunities, address 18+ product problems, and implement 12+ scalable product solutions, driving enhanced user engagement and satisfaction.

Robust.Ai • San Carlos, CA, USA • 08/2022 - 11/2022

Ux Research Intern

- Worked directly under the director of research and head of product to apply interviewing, ethnography, and observational techniques to consult clients, inform research directions, and guide product design, resulting in improved user experience and informed research directions to achieve business goals.
- Presented research insights/summaries and informed design directions and communicated product directions from a user-centered point of view to help the internal team to understand what the product needs to do
- Utilized UX research methods to improve external validity on in-house studies, inform business product design and drive strategic decisions, enhancing user experience and satisfaction. Delivered actionable insights in user-centric design, resulting in improved user experience and informed product decisions in just 3 months.

User Empowerment Lab, University Of Washington Information School •

06/2019 - 09/2020

Research Assistant

• Led a research project development process covering study design, recruitment, and qualitative analysis, resulting in actionable findings for product development and design improvement.

SKILLS

Ajax, Benchmarking, Chatbot, communication, communication skills, Computer Science, contextual inquiry, Curiosity, detailoriented, Educational Research, email, Ethnography, Field Research, figma, Health Informatics, Human-Centered Design, Human Factors and Ergonomics, Inclusive, interpersonal skills, Interviewing Process, JavaScript, Learning, Passion, personas, PHP, presentations, problem solving, product management, product roadmap, Project Analysis, Python, Qualitative Research, Research, research and insights, research strategy, SQL, Strong leadership, Teamwork, TikTok, User Interface, User Research, UX Writing, Video Interview, Virtual Reality, Visual Design, writing

EDUCATION

Master's Of Science Computational Media

University Of California Santa Cruz, California, USA 09/2020 - 03/2024 Conducted and analyzed participant studies using interviews, WoZ, and qualitative
analysis to examine social effects of new software voice interfaces on children,
informing user-centric design decisions. Project incorporated discussion of
cognition and child psychology.

Prosocial Computing Lab, University Of Washington • 04/2017 - 06/2020

Research Assistant

- Built qualitative and quantitative research skills advised by Prof. Gary Hsieh in the Human-Centered Design & Engineering Department
- Helped to design, execute, and analyze participant interviews on-site at local hospital, joint project w/Prof. Andrea Hartzler of University of Washington Biomedical Informatics on usability of hospital emergency room chatbot design published with Conversational User Interfaces (CUI) 2021.
- Designed and analyzed study of eye-tracking and webpage behavior, constructed local database for quantitative data using Apache, SQL, and PHP and tracked through Python, JavaScript, and AJAX which led to more user data points.

University Of Washington • 09/2018 - 06/2019

Marketing And Communications

- Thrived in collaborative environment with cross-functional marketing team to consult and improve content across the university's websites on an interdisciplinary team with developers, designers, and content strategists.
- Conducted user research to draw insights and make improvements on web campaigns, programs, and communications

Computing Research Association, University Of Iowa • 06/2018 - 09/2018

Visiting Research Assistant

- HCI/Accessibility research advised by Prof. Kyle Rector in the Computer Science dept. at the University of Iowa as part of CRA's Distributed Research Experience for Undergrads (DREU)
- Qualitatively coded videos, transcribed and analysed interviews on inclusive design for blind users in Virtual Reality. Published with Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI) 2019.

PROJECTS

Optimizing Canvas LMS for Enhanced Online Learning Experience •

12/2019 - 06/2020

UX Research Project: Canvas LMS Optimization

- Collaborated with UW Continuum College to generate new features including inapp messaging for the Canvas Learning Management System (LMS) for an enhanced online learning experience
- Utilized the human-centered design process to identify areas for improvement and reduce cognitive load, including competitive analysis and concept testing.
- Demonstrated skills in user research, visual design, prototyping, usability testing, stakeholder collaboration, and problem-solving

Bs In Human Centered Design & Engineering

University Of Washington Seattle, Washington, USA 06/2016 - 06/2020

VOLUNTEERING & LEADERSHIP

Society of Women Engineers

President

Lead UW's largest student-run organization consisting of 20+ officers and 300+ members to promote diversity and inclusion in engineering with focus on professional development and K-12 outreach through both independent and collaborative team events with other engineering groups, local organizations, and industry.